A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Audiovisual Materials, RG 7 FA1801
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Photographs, 1890-2019; 5; 5.08 Cubic Feet 12 containers
  - Programs, 1982-2006; 5; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
    - Community Initiatives, 1993-1994; 2
      - Community Initiatives: Habitat for Humanity, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Knight File Number - 844
        Two undated photographs of a Habitat for Humanity Projects. One is an image of Jimmy Carter holding a hammer, unidentified location (Miami Herald photo). Black and white.
      - Community Initiatives, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Knight File Number - 863
        Photographs and negatives taken, but not used for the Community Initiatives section of the 1993 Annual Report. Black & white.
      - Community Initiatives in Annual Report, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Knight File Number - 874
        Photographs taken for the Community Initiatives section of the 1994 Annual Report. Black & white.
      - Immunization Initiative, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Knight File Number - 875
        Photograph taken to illustrate the Immunization Initiative in the Knight Foundation Newsletter, 1994. Black & white.
      - Community Initiatives, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Knight File Number - 876
        Photographs taken of Community Initiatives projects in 1994. Not used in any publication. Black & white.
    - Education, 1989-1994; 3
      - Education: Centre College, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Knight File Number - 848
        Photographs from Centre College (Education Program). Pictured are various students and professors, ca. 1989. Black & white.
      - Education: Davidson College, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Knight File Number - 849
        Photographs from Davidson College (Education Program). Pictured are various students and professors, ca. 1989. Black & white.
      - Education: Kalamazoo College, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        Knight File Number - 850
        Photographs from Kalamazoo College (Education Program). Pictured are various students and professors, ca. 1989. Black & white.
      - Education: Macalester College, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        Knight File Number - 851
        Photographs from Macalester College (Education Program). Pictured are various students and professors, ca. 1989. Black & white.
      - Education: Swarthmore College, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        Knight File Number - 852
        Photographs from Swarthmore College (Education Program). Pictured are various students and professors, ca. 1989. Black & white.
      - Education Program: Ruby Middleton Forsythe (teacher), South Carolina, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
        Knight File Number - 857
        Two folders, one with photographs taken for the Education Program section of the 1992 Annual Report. (Ruby Middleton Forsythe by Cecilia Konyn for The Sun News of Myrtle Beach, SC. Black & white.
      - Education Program: California State University, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        Knight File Number - 858
        Photographs taken for the Education Program section of the 1992 Annual Report, but not used. Excellence in Education Program. Black & white.
      - Education Program: Juniata College, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        Knight File Number - 859
        Photographs taken for the Education Program section of the 1992 Annual Report, but not used. Photographs of Juniata College by Tracey D. Huston. Black & white.
      - Education Program in Annual Report, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Knight File Number - 864
        Photographs and negatives taken for the Education program section of the 1993 Annual Report. Black & white.
      - Education Program, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        Knight File Number - 865
        Photographs, negatives and transparencies taken, but not used in, the Education program section of the 1993 Annual Report.
      - Excellence in Undergraduate Education Conference, 1993 June (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Knight File Number - 866
        Photographs taken on the set of "Firing Line," at the Excellence in Undergraduate Education Conference in Columbia, MD in June, 1993. Not used in any publication. Black & white.
      - Excellence in Undergraduate Education Conference in Publications, 1993 June (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Knight File Number - 867
        Photographs taken on the set of "Firing Line," at the Excellence in Undergraduate Education Conference in Columbia, MD in June, 1993. Used in 1993 annual report, page 39, and in Knight Foundation Newsletter, July 1993. Black & white.
      - Education Program, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        Knight File Number - 877
        Photographs taken for the Education Program section of the Annual Report, 1994. Black & white.
      - Education Program, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        Knight File Number - 878
        Photographs and negatives taken, but not used, for the Education Program section of the Annual Report, 1994. Black & white.
    - Journalism, 1982-1995; 4
      - Journalism: MIT Knight Science Journalism Fellowship Program, 1995 January-October 20 (Box 1, Folder 38)
        Knight File Number - 845
        Photographs and negatives of participants in the Knight Science Journalism Fellowship Program at MIT (Journalism program). Includes image of Creed Black, Lee Hills, Jim Spaniolo, and Del Brinkman taken in January 1995. (B&W and color snapshots.)
      - Journalism: University of Florida, Minority Recruitment & Retention Program, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
        Knight File Number - 846
        Undated photographs of participants in the Minority Recruitment & Retention Program at the University of Florida (Journalism Program). Black & white.
      - Journalism: Stanford University, John S. Knight Professional Journalism Fellowship, 1982 May 27 (Box 1, Folder 39)
        Knight File Number - 847
        Photographs from Stanford University, John S. Knight Professional Journalism Fellowship, 1982. Pictured are Lee Hills, C.C. Gibson, President Donald Kennedy of Stanford, and Vice-President and Provost Albert Hastorf of Stanford. Black & white.
      - Journalism: MIT Science Journalism Fellowship Program, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        Knight File Number - 853
        Photograph of 1989 Fellows from the MIT Science Journalism Fellowship Program. Photo by Paula M. Lerner, Cambridge, MA. Black & white.
      - Journalism: University of Missouri-Columbia School of Journalism, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
        Knight File Number - 854
        Photographs from the University of Missouri-Columbia School of Journalism, Minority Recruitment and Retention Program (Journalism Program). Photographs of students and professors, including captions. Black & white.
      - Journalism Program in Annual Report, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        Knight File Number - 868
        Photographs taken for the Journalism Program section of the 1993 Annual Report. Black & white.
      - Journalism Program, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
        Knight File Number - 869
        Photographs taken for, but not used in, the Journalism Program section of the 1993 Annual Report. Black & white.
      - Journalism Program in Annual Report, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
        Knight File Number - 879
        Photographs taken for the Journalism Program section in the 1994 Annual Report. Includes a photo of Reese Cleghorn by Edward H. Remsburg. Black & white.
      - Journalism Program, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 33)
        Knight File Number - 880
        Photographs taken for, but not used in, the Journalism Program section in the 1994 Annual Report. Black & white.
      - Journalism Program: Indiana University, Desktop Publishing Class (used in Annual Report, 1995) (Box 1, Folder 37)
        Knight File Number - 884
        Indiana University, image taken during "Desktop Publishing Class." Photograph taken for the Journalism Program section of the 1995 Annual Report. (8"x10" B&W)
      - John S. Knight Journalism Chairholders, 1995 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 34)
        Knight File Number - 886
        Photographs taken of the John S. Knight Journalism Chairholders at a meeting of the Chairs on 3/10/95. Pictured are Phil Meyer, Joe Ritchie, John Ginn, and Jim Detjen. Black & white.
      - ASNE Institute for Journalism Excellence, 1995 May 30-August 31 (Box 1, Folder 35)
        Knight File Number - 887
        Photographs and negatives taken of the American Society of Newspaper Editors (ASNE) Institute for Journalism Excellence program. Black & white and color.
      - Journalism: Stanford University: John S. Knight Latin American Journalism Fellowship, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        Knight File Number - 888
        Photograph of Carlos Cano, the John S. Knight Latin American Journalism Fellow at Stanford University, with Jim Risser, director of the program in 1995. Photo by Russell D. Curtis. Black & white.
      - Journalism: Walter Cronkite Luncheon at Arizona State University, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 36)
        Knight File Number - 889
        Photographs of Del Brinkman speaking at the Walter Cronkite Luncheon at Arizona State University in 1995. Photos by Mike Cooper. Black & white.
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, Key Biscayne, FL, 1997 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 3294
      Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat in Key Biscayne, FL. 12 b/w photos of participants. Murry Sill, photographer.
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, St. Paul, MN, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 3295
      Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat in St. Paul. Contains 5 contact sheets only. Contact Doug Knutson for reprints and authorization.
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Advisory Committee Meeting, 1999 June (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 3296
      Magic of Music Orchestra Advisory Committee Meeting, New Orleans, LA, June 1999. 7 color photos, including Tom Wolf, MofM consultant and Fred Starr, Chairman of the Advisory Committee. Jackson Hill photographer.
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, Charlotte, NC, 2000 May 19-21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 3297
      Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat at the Mayfair House in Coconut Grove, Miami, FL. 4 color photographs (4x6). Includes Knight staffers Suzette (Prude) Harvey and Gary Burger, violinist Nicole Cherry, and MofM speakers Margo Puleo and Eugene Carr. Unknown photographer.
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, Charlotte, NC, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 3019
      Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat for orchestra directors in Charlotte, North Carolina. 5 4"x6" color photo. Individuals featured include Penny McPhee; Marion Godfrey, Pew Charitable Trusts; Peter Pennekamp, Humboldt Area Foundation; and Ellen Albeiding, President, Joyce Foundation. NOTE: Contact the photographer at LOF Productions for authorization and JPEGs.
    - John S. and James L. Knight Concert Hall, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 5875
      Color photographs of the concert hall in Miami. Includes high and low resolution photos on cd and slides.
    - John S. and James L. Knight Concert Hall - Low Res Photos (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - John S. and James L. Knight Concert Hall - High Res Photos (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sound Recordings, 1978-2004; 6; 0.43 Cubic Feet 2 oversize document boxes
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 1 - Curriculum Development, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15900)
    Knight File Number - 1145
    Panel and presentations from the Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges, held at the Columbia Inn in Columbia, MD on June 10-12. 1993.
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 2 - Libraries and Info., 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15901)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 3 - Curriculum Development, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15902)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 4 - Curriculum Development, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15903)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 5 - Libraries and Info., 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15904)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 6 - Student Recruitment and Retention, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15905)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 7 - Student Recruitment and Retention, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15906)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 8 - Student Recruitment and Retention, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15907)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 9 - Looking Ahead, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15908)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 10 - Looking Ahead, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15909)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 11 - Looking Ahead, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15910)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 12 - Diversity, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15911)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 13 - Diversity, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15912)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 14 - Diversity, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15913)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 15 - Lunch, Rouse, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15914)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 16 - Dr. Cornel West, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15915)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 17 - Libraries and Info., 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15916)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 18 - Lessons from Distinctive Missions, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15917)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 19 - Faculty/Student Research, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15918)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 20 - Dinner, Dr. Cornel West, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15919)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 21 - Lessons from Distinctive Missions, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15920)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 22 - Lessons from Distinctive Missions, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15921)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 23 - Faculty Development, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15922)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 24 - Faculty Development, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15923)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 25 - Faculty Development, 1993 June 10; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15924)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 26 - Faculty/Student Research, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15925)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 27 - Faculty/Student Research, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15926)
  - Excellence in Education Dissemination Conference for Liberal Arts Colleges - Tape 28 - Faculty/Student Research, 1993 June 11; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15927)
  - Memorial Service for James L. Knight, Church by the Sea, Bal Harbour, Florida, 1991 February 13; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15928)
    Knight File Number - 2424
    Cassette tape recording of memorial service for James L. Knight, February 13, 1991 at the Church by the Sea, Bal Harbour, Florida
  - Remarks at Communications Network Seminar, Miami Beach, 1998 October 1; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15929)
    Knight File Number - 2411
    Cassette tape recording of remarks by Hodding Carter at the Communications Network Seminar, part of the C.O.F. Conference, held in Miami Beach in October 1998.
  - Knight Commission Report on College Sports, 2002 April 9; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15930)
    Knight File Number - 1976
    One audio cassette re: "Knight Commission Report of College Sports". This is recorded commentary on the following radio shows: Paul Harvey, CBS-AM and Talk of the Nation.
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 1 - 1st Session, Educators, 1995 January 16; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15931)
    Knight File Number - 2425
    Journalism educators discuss journalism education and the newspaper industry.
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 2 - 1st Session, 1995 January 16; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15932)
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 3 - 2nd Session, 1995 January 16; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15933)
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 4 - 2nd Session, 1995 January 16; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15934)
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 5 - 2nd Session, 1995 January 16; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15935)
  - Interview with John S. Knight by Dan Neuharth - Tape 1, 1978 October 24; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15936)
    Knight File Number - 4415
    Dan Neuharth's interview with John S. Knight.
  - Interview with John S. Knight by Dan Neuharth - Tape 2, 1978 October 24; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15937)
  - South Florida Business Focus: Interview with Creed Black, 1996 January 02; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15938)
    Knight File Number - 818
    Interview with Creed Black on radio statio WLRN program, South Florida Business Focus. The interview originally aired on 1/2/96 at 7:00 pm and was conducted by Larry Burger.
  - Business Focus with Larry Burger: Interview with Creed Black, 1997 January 23; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15939)
    Knight File Number 818
    Interview with Creed Black on radio statio WLRN program, South Florida Business Focus. The interview aired at 7:00 pm and was conducted by Larry Burger.
  - Sharpen the Focus and Heighten the Impact Cities Program Associates Meeting - Rod Petrey, Creed Black, Lee Hills (Part 1), 1995 January 17; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15940)
    Knight File Number - 2485
    Meeting involving Knight Foundation staff and consultants and Knight-Ridder community associates (later advisors). The meeting was designed to provide the associates with information about Knight's strategic planning process and to gather input from the group on how to make the process better. Included are remarks by Lee Hills, Creed Black, Rod Petrey (Foundation legal counsel), Rolfe Neill, and James Batten. A small amount of the group discussion was recorded.
  - Sharpen the Focus and Heighten the Impact Cities Program Associates Meeting - Creed Black, Rolfe Neill, Jim Batten, Group Discussion (Part 2), 1995 January 17; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15941)
  - Speech by Creed Black to the Akron Roundtable, 1990 January 18; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15942)
    Knight File Number - 2557
    One audio cassette of speech made by Creed Black to the Akron Roundtable. A question and answer period is at the end. Topics include relocation of Knight Foundation, the Knight Commission of ICA, and Akron area grants.
  - Knight Foundation 50th Anniversary Mission Awareness, 2000; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15943)
    Knight File Number - 2558
    On-air underwriting credit on National Public Radio, "Support for National Public Radio comes from the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation, working for 50 years to enhance the quality of life in communities and to support a free press."
  - Council on Foundations Annual Meeting, 2004; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15944)
    Knight File Number - 4790
    Session: Leadership Challenge: The Communications Priority features Hodding Carter on the panel. Tape is labeled 1 of 2 but is the only one in the collection.
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 1, 1995 January 17; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15945)
    Knight File Number - 2426
    Editors discuss the state of journalism education.
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 2, 1995 January 17; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15946)
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 3, 1995 January 17; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15947)
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 4, 1995 January 17; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15948)
  - Journalism Focus Group Meeting - Tape 5, 1995 January 17; Audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15949)
- Transparencies, 1970-2003; 7; 0.19 Cubic Feet 1 half-letter box
  - Events, 1995; 1; 0.06 Cubic Feet
    - Lee Hills Hall Dedication, 1995 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 816
      33 slides of images from the Compact Disk created to celebrate the dedication of Lee Hills Hall. Contains photographs of Lee Hills from his childhood through his career.
  - People, 1970-2003; 2; 0.07 Cubic Feet
    - People - A-Z, 1970-1998; 2.1
      - John S. and James L. Knight in printing room, c. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 4410
        Negative of the brothers in a printing room. Image of portrait on display in KF headquarters. Also included is a cd of the image, in color, in a highest resolution tif file.
      - John S. and James L. Knight in printing room - High Resolution TIFF file (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Black, Creed C., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Knight File Number - 1391
        Informal portraits of Mr. Black by Pelham Photographic Services.
      - Knight Foundation Staff and Trustees, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Knight File Number - 2402
        Individual portraits (negatives only) of Knight Foundation staff and trustees taken for the 1998 Annual Report.
    - People - Groups, 1987-2003; 2.2
      - Board of Trustees, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Knight File Number - 946
        Group photograph of the Board of Trustees for the 1987 annual report. Includes Alvah Chapman, Barbara Toomey, Henry King Stanford, C.C. Gibson, Gerald Austen, Lee Hills and James L. Knight. Negatives only. Color.
      - Board of Trustees, 1989 December 31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Knight File Number - 815
        Six slides of a photograph of the Board of Trustees taken ca. 1989 for the annual report. The photographer was Lynn Pelham. Pictured are: James L. Knight, Lee Hills, Alvah Chapman, Barbara Knight Toomey, Henry King Stanford, C.C. Gibson and Gordon Heffern.
      - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, 2002 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Knight File Number - 3298
        Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat in Portland, Oregeon. Four sheets of negatives, with contact sheets. Alan Borrud, photographer.
      - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, 2003 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Knight File Number - 3014
        Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat at Brooklyn, New York. Slides are of participants and include Penny McPhee, Lisa Versaci, and MofM consultant Tom Wolf. Includes a demonstration of the Concert Companion on PDA (a hand-held computer with screen) by Roland Valiere. Contains 200 slides in sleeves. Most labeled.